Earl Browder Papers
Earl Browder Papers
- Correspondence-subject files
  - American Slav Anti-Hitler Congress, 1942 (Box 3)
  - The American Socialist, 1957 (Box 3)
  - American Society for Technical Aid to Spanish Democracy, 1937 (Box 3)
  - American-Soviet Musical Society, 1947 (Box 3)
  - American Writers' Congress, 1935 (Box 3)
  - American Youth Congress, 1936; 1940 (Box 3)
  - "America's Town Meeting of the Air", See Town Hall, Inc.
  - Amter, Israel, 1942; 1945 (Box 3)
  - Analysis, 1945 (Box 3)
  - Anderson, Clinton P., See United States House of Representatives Special Committee on Campaign Expenditures
  - Anderson, Edith, 1942 (Box 3)
  - Angell, Norman, 1935 (Box 3)
  - Anthony Productions, Inc., 1971 (Box 3)
  - Anti-Communist legislation, 1943 (Box 3)
  - Anti-Defamation League, 1940 (Box 3)
  - Anti-Hitlerism and Latin America, 1941-1943 (Box 3)
  - Anti-Semitism, 1943 (Box 3)
  - Appelman, Mike, 1939 (Box 3)
  - [D.] Appleton-Century Company, Inc, 1946 (Box 3)
  - Arakcheyev, Alexey Andreyevich, undated (Box 3)
  - Archway Book Store, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1948 (Box 3)
  - Arco Publishing Company, 1946 (Box 3)
  - Argentina, 1943; 1944 (Box 3)
  - Argosy, 1947 (Box 3)
  - Armenians in America, 1942 (Box 3)
  - Army & Navy Journal, 1947 (Box 3)
  - Army Ordnance, 1947 (Box 3)
  - Aronow, Edward I., 1939 (Box 3)
  - Aronsberg, Emanuel, 1925 (Box 3)
  - Arze, José Antonio, 1942-1945 (Box 3)
  - Associated Press, 1963 (Box 3)
  - Atlanta Constitution, 1944 (Box 3)
  - Atlantic City High School, 1948 (Box 3)
  - The Atlantic Monthly, 1946-1948 (Box 3)
  - Auer, William, 1945 (Box 3)
  - Auerbach, Isabel, 1936 (Box 3)
  - Auld, James C., 1960; 1961,; 1964 (Box 3)
  - "The Author Meets the Critics," WQXR Radio, 1947 (Box 3)
  - B, 1935-1955 (Box 3)
  - Bachrach, Marion, undated (Box 3)
  - Bacon Pamphlet Service, 1948 (Box 3)
  - Baker, Hart E., 1945 (Box 3)
  - Baker, Rudy, See Blum, Rudolph.
  - [Walter H.] Baker Company, 1947 (Box 3)
  - Baker & Taylor Company (Box 3)
  - Baldwin, Roger, 1941 (Box 3)
  - Bannister, L. Ward, 1945 (Box 3)
  - Barden, Leonard, 1957 (Box 3)
  - Baruch, Bernard Mannes, 1926 (Box 3)
  - Bassols, Narciso, 1942 (Box 3)
  - Bates, Ralph, 1943 (Box 3)
  - [Eugene] Bechtold, Bookseller, 1948 (Box 4)
  - Bedacht, Max, See American Fund for Public Service.
  - Bednarski, Sigmund, 1943 (Box 4)
  - Beechhurst Press, Inc., 1947 (Box 4)
  - Bell, Daniel, See The Fund for the Republic, Inc.
  - Bell, Tom Jay, 1943 (Box 4)
  - [Matthew] Bender & Company, 1947 (Box 4)
  - Beneš, Edvard, 1943 (Box 4)
  - Benjamin, Herbert, 1942 (Box 4)
  - Berenson, Mitchell, 1946 (Box 4)
  - Berg, Philip, 1942 (Box 4)
  - Berkmann, Mary, 1935-1962 (Box 4)
  - Berkmann, S.B. (Bernard), 1936-1938 (Box 4)
  - Beria, Lavrenty Pavlovich, 1938 (Box 4)
  - Berkowitz, Sylvia, 1954-1965 (Box 4)
  - Bernard, John Toussaint, 1937 (Box 4)
  - Bernaut, Elsa, 1961-1964 (Box 4)
  - Berti, Giuseppe, 1944 (Box 4)
  - Bessie, Alvah, 1942 (Box 4)
  - Bethune, Henry Norman, 1938 (Box 4)
  - Biddle, Francis, undated (Box 4)
  - Billboard, 1947 (Box 4)
  - Biller, David Wolfe, 1946 (Box 4)
  - Birkhead, Leon Milton, 1940 (Box 4)
  - Birobidjan, See American Committee for the Resettlement of Jews in Birobidjan.
  - Bishop, Rufus Walter, 1944 (Box 4)
  - Bittleman, Alexander, 1925; 1937,; 1938,; 1943,; 1944 (Box 4)
  - Black Legion, 1936; 1941 (Box 4)
    See also Ku Klux Klan
  - Bliven, Bruce, See New Republic
  - Blossom, Frederick A., undated (Box 4)
  - Blum, Rudolph and Lilly, 1951-1970; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Blum, Rudolph [?] writing as Ralph Bowman (pseudonym), undated (Box 4)
  - The Bobbs-Merrill Company, 1947 (Box 4)
  - Bohn, William E., 1945 (Box 4)
  - Bolivia, 1944 (Box 4)
  - Bolivian Democratic Union, 1944 (Box 4)
  - Bolshevik, 1947-1949 (Box 4)
  - Boni & Gaer, Inc, 1947-1949 (Box 5)
  - Bonnier's New York, NY, 1948 (Box 5)
  - Bonus Book Club, Inc, 1948 (Box 5)
  - Book Find Club, 1943 (Box 5)
  - Bookbinding and Book Production, 1946; 1947 (Box 5)
  - Books Abroad, 1947 (Box 5)
  - "Books on Trial," WHN Radio, 1946; 1947 (Box 5)
  - Boston Evening Transcript, 1939 (Box 5)
  - Boudin, Louis B., 1943; 1951-1957 (Box 5)
  - Braman, Robert E., "Boston Coastwise shipping", undated (Box 5)
  - Branch, William E. (pseudonym), See Browder, William (brother of E.B.)
  - Brandt & Brandt, 1946 (Box 5)
  - Bransten, Richard, 1941-1944 (Box 5)
  - Brant, Neil, 1943; 1944 (Box 5)
  - Brazil, 1940 (Box 5)
  - Braziller, George, See Book Find Club.
  - Brentano's, 1948 (Box 5)
  - Bridges, Harry Renton, 1942-1946 (Box 5)
  - Brisman, Chaim, 1946 (Box 5)
  - British Consulate General, Shanghai, China, 1936 (Box 5)
  - Broadcast Music, Inc., 1946 (Box 5)
  - Brodsky, Carl, 1943; 1946 (Box 5)
  - Bronx (NY) Workers Athletic Club, 1930 (Box 5)
  - Browder, Andrew, 1938-1965; undated (Box 5)
  - Browder, Anna (Mrs. James), 1937 (Box 6)
  - Browder, Earl
    - China visit, 1942 (Box 6)
    - Subpoenas, 1935-1955 (Box 6)
    - To Irene Browder, 1935-1946 (Box 6)
    - To/from Irene Browder, 1941; 1942,; 1950; letters from prison; 3 folders (Box 6)
    - To/from family, 1934-1942 (Box 6)
  - Browder, Felix, 1930s (Box 6)
  - Browder, Felix, 1941-1951; 1953-1966; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Browder, Frank G., 1956 (Box 7)
  - Browder, Gladys L., 1963 (Box 7)
  - Browder, Grace Ida Smiley, 1945 (Box 7)
  - Browder, Irene
    - [General], 1950; undated (Box 7)
    - To Earl Browder, 1929-1937; 1945 (Box 7)
    - Condolences, 1955 (Box 7)
    - Death, 1955 (Box 7)
  - Browder, Jay, 1937 (Box 7)
  - Browder, Julie, undated (Box 7)
  - Browder, Ralph Waldo, 1937-1969 (Box 7)
  - Browder, Ruth, 1939 (Box 7)
  - Browder, William (father of E.B.), 1919-1943 (Box 7)
  - Browder, William (brother of E.B.), 1926-1956 (Box 7)
  - Browder, William (son of E.B.), 1942-1964 (Box 7)
  - [Earl] Browder, Inc., 1949-1951 (Box 8)
  - [Earl] Browder, Inc., 1946; 1947; lists, outlines and synopses of books offered; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Brown, Elizabeth Churchill, 1955; 1957,; 1964 (Box 8)
  - Brown, William Montgomery, 1936; 1938,; 1939 (Box 8)
  - [Curtis] Brown, Ltd., 1946 (Box 8)
  - Brown University Library, 1948 (Box 8)
  - Bryan, Helen R., 1942 (Box 8)
  - Bryant Book Shop, New York, NY, 1948 (Box 8)
  - Bubbenov, Michael, 1948 (Box 8)
  - Buck, Pearl Sydenstricker, See Lloyd, David.
  - Buck, Timothy, 1942 (Box 8)
    See also Communist Party, Canada.
  - Budenz, Louis F., 1939; 1943 (Box 8)
  - Buell, Raymond Leslie, See Foreign Policy Association.
  - Bulgaria, 1945 (Box 8)
  - Burke, J. Frank, Sr., 1939 (Box 8)
  - Burma, 1943 (Box 8)
  - Burtan, Valentine Gregory, 1940 (Box 8)
  - Business Girl, 1947 (Box 8)
  - Business Men of America, Inc., 1945 (Box 8)
  - Business Week, 1947 (Box 8)
  - Butler, John Marshall, 1958 (Box 8)
  - Butler, Mary, 1958 (Box 8)
  - Bynner, Harold Witter, 1942 (Box 8)
  - Byrd, Harry Flood, Sr., 1957 (Box 8)
  - C, 1930-1961 (Box 8)
  - Cacchione, Peter V., 1945 (Box 8)
  - California Department of Industrial Relations, 1942 (Box 8)
  - California State Senate Fact-Finding Committee on Un-American Activities, 1948 (Box 8)
  - California v. Harry Jackson, 1935 (Box 8)
  - Camp Ripley, Minnesota, undated (Box 8)
  - La Cancion de Stalingrado, Manzanilla, Cuba, 1943 (Box 8)
  - Capitol Publishing Company, 1947 (Box 8)
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, 1947 (Box 8)
  - Carnegie Library of Pittsburgh, 1948 (Box 8)
  - Carolina Political Union, 1938; undated (Box 8)
  - Carpeña, Pépita, undated (Box 8)
  - Carter, Jimmy, 1976 (Box 8)
  - Casselberry, Horace, 1941 (Box 8)
  - Catholic Labor Alliance, Chicago, Illinois, 1943 (Box 8)
  - Cattell & Co., 1949 (Box 8)
  - Celler, Emanuel, 1944 (Box 8)
  - Cenacle Press, 1948 (Box 8)
  - Central Committee of War Veterans Organizations of Yonkers (NY), 1944 (Box 8)
  - Central Missouri State College, Warrensburg, Missouri, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Cerf, Bennett A., See Random House, Inc.
  - Chafee, Zechariah, Jr., 1944 (Box 8)
  - Chamberlin, William Henry, 1945 (Box 8)
  - Chambers, Whittaker, 1952 (Box 8)
  - Chatto & Windus, Ltd., London, 1960 (Box 8)
  - Chaunt, Peter, 1937; 1957 (Box 8)
  - Chemical Publishing Company, Inc., 1946-1960 (Box 8)
  - Chen Chia-Keng, undated (Box 8)
  - Cheprakov, V., 1948 (Box 9)
  - The Chicago Sun, 1947 (Box 9)
  - Chile, 1940; 1943 (Box 9)
  - China, 1942-1944 (Box 9)
  - China, Ministry of Foreign Affairs, 1941 (Box 9)
  - China Aid Council, 1942 (Box 9)
  - Chkalov, Valeri, 1947 (Box 9)
  - The Christian Front, 1940 (Box 9)
  - The Christian Register, 1947 (Box 9)
  - The Christian Science Monitor, 1947; 1954 (Box 9)
  - Church League for Industrial Democracy, 1942 (Box 9)
  - The Citadel Press, 1946-1948; 1963 (Box 9)
  - Citizens' Committee to Free Earl Browder, 1941 (Box 9)
  - City College of New York, 1948 (Box 9)
  - Clark, Delbert, See What's On Your Mind?, WQXR Radio.
  - [Charles W.] Clark Company, 1948 (Box 9)
  - Classic Comics, See Gilberton Company.
  - Cleath, Robert L., 1962; 1963 (Box 9)
  - Cleveland Public Library, 1948 (Box 9)
  - Cobb, Richard, 1964 (Box 9)
  - Cochran, Bert, See The American Socialist.
  - Cockcroft, Julia Walcott, 1941 (Box 9)
  - College Book Exchange, Toledo, Ohio, 1948 (Box 9)
  - College Book Store, Ames, Iowa, 1948 (Box 9)
  - Colliers, 1944; 1945,; 1947 (Box 9)
  - Colonial House Publishers, 1947-1948 (Box 9)
  - Colonial Radio Corporation, Buffalo, NY, 1943 (Box 9)
  - Columbia Broadcasting System, Inc., 1944; 1946 (Box 9)
  - Columbia University, 1946; 1947,; 1962 (Box 9)
  - Columbia University Book Store, 1948 (Box 9)
  - Columbia University Oral History Project, 1964; 1971 (Box 9)
  - Columbia University Press, 1946; 1948 (Box 9)
  - The Comet Press, Inc., 1948 (Box 9)
  - Commission to Study the Organization of Peace, 1944 (Box 9)
  - Committee for Concerted Peace Efforts, 1938 (Box 9)
  - Committee for Economic Development, 1946 (Box 9)
  - Committee for the Promotion of Democracy, 1941 (Box 9)
  - Communist International, 1930 (Box 10)
  - Communist International Magazine, 1934 (Box 10)
  - Communist Party, Algeria, 1943 (Box 10)
  - Communist Party, American-Canadian Group, 1929 (Box 10)
  - Communist Party, Argentina, 1939-1946 (Box 10)
  - Communist Party, Australia, 1944; 1945,; 1948 (Box 10)
  - Communist Party, Austria, 1935 (Box 10)
  - Communist Party, Bolivia, 1943 (Box 10)
  - Communist Party, Brazil, 1943-1945; undated (Box 10)
  - Communist Party, Canada, 1922; 1942,; undated (Box 10)
  - Communist Party, Chile, 1936; 1940,; 1942,; undated (Box 10)
  - Communist Party, China, 1936; 1940,; 1942,; undated (Box 10)
  - Communist Party, Colombia, 1944; 1945 (Box 10)
  - Communist Party, Costa Rica, 1943 (Box 10)
  - Communist Party, Cuba, 1941-1948 (Box 10)
  - Communist Party, Czechoslovakia, 1948 (Box 10)
  - Communist Party, Executive Committee of the Communist International, 1931; 1939,; 1943 (Box 10)
  - Communist Party, France, 1942-1944 (Box 10)
  - Communist Party, Germany, 1929; 1939 (Box 10)
  - Communist Party, Great Britain, 1945; 1948,; undated (Box 10)
  - Communist Party, Greece, 1944; 1946 (Box 10)
  - Communist Party, Haiti, 1946 (Box 11)
  - Communist Party, Honduras, 1944 (Box 11)
  - Communist Party, Hungary, 1945; undated (Box 11)
  - Communist Party, India, 1938; 1942 (Box 11)
  - Communist Party, Ireland, 1942; 1943 (Box 11)
  - Communist Party, Italy, 1940; 1945,; 1948,; 1959 (Box 11)
  - Communist Party, Latin American Secretariat of the Communist International, 1930 (Box 11)
  - Communist Party, Mexico, 1930-1945 (Box 11)
  - Communist Party, Morocco, undated (Box 11)
  - Communist Party, New Zealand, 1942; 1943 (Box 11)
  - Communist Party, Peru, 1938; 1942 (Box 11)
  - Communist Party, Philippines, 1936; 1938,; 1945 (Box 11)
  - Communist Party, Poland, 1948 (Box 11)
  - Communist Party, Puerto Rico, 1934 (Box 11)
  - Communist Party, Spain
    - [General], 1938; 1943,; 1944,; undated (Box 11)
    - Communist Party, Spain "Al Partido Communista de España de los Communistas de la XV Brigada Internacional", 1938 (Box 11)
    - Scrapbook, 1936-1947 (Box 12)
  - Communist Party, Spain in North Africa, 1941; 1942 (Box 12)
  - Communist Party, South Africa, 1944; 1945 (Box 12)
  - Communist Party, USA
    - Bulgarian-Macedonian Bureau, 1940 (Box 12)
    - Cadre & Review Commission, 1948 (Box 12)
    - California State Committee, 1942 (Box 12)
    - Central Committee, 1937-1945 (Box 12)
    - Central Committee memoranda, 1930; 1942-1945 (Box 12)
    - Central Committee Plenum summary of discussion, 31 Mar - 4 Apr, 1930; 3 folders (Box 12)
    - Central Committee Plenum, 1939 (Box 12)
    - Central Executive Committee, Trade Union Committee, 1926; 1927; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Chicago Convention, 1923 (Box 13)
    - Conference of Miners, 30 Apr 1927 (Box 13)
    - Constitution, undated (Box 13)
    - District # 2, 1931 (Box 13)
    - District #8, Chicago, Illinois, 1930 (Box 13)
    - Elections, 1930 (Box 13)
    - Elections, 1932 (Box 13)
    - Elections, 1936 (Box 13)
    - Elections, 1938 (Box 13)
    - Elections, 1940 (Box 13)
    - Elections, 1942 (Box 13)
    - Elections, 1944 (Box 13)
    - Financial statements, 1939; 1944 (Box 13)
    - Finnish Bureau, 1929 (Box 13)
    - French pamphlet distribution, 1943 (Box 13)
    - Language Federations, undated (Box 13)
    - Language work, 1936 (Box 13)
    - Membership books, 1930; 1942,; 1943,; 1945 (Box 13)
    - Membership drive, 1944 (Box 13)
    - Monroe County, NY, 1944 (Box 13)
    - National Committee, 1938-1946 (Box 13)
    - National Convention (6th), 1929 (Box 13)
    - National Convention (7th), 1930 (Box 13)
    - National Convention (8th), 1934 (Box 13)
    - National Convention (9th), 1936 (Box 14)
    - National Convention (10th), 1938 (Box 14)
    - National Convention (12th), 1944 (Box 14)
    - National Convention (13th), 1945 (Box 14)
    - National Convention (14th), 1948 (Box 14)
    - National Convention (16th), 1956 (Box 14)
    - National Convention, undated (Box 14)
    - National Farm Commission, undated (Box 14)
    - National groups, 1944 (Box 14)
    - National Training School, 1930 (Box 14)
    - New York City Central Committee, 1934 (Box 14)
    - New York State, 1937; 1943-1945 (Box 14)
    - Ohio, 1943 (Box 14)
    - Oregon, 1942 (Box 14)
    - Pennsylvania State Committee, 1943 (Box 14)
    - Plenum, 1937 (Box 14)
    - Political Bureau, 1930 (Box 14)
    - Political Committee, 1927; 1929,; 1939 (Box 14)
    - Press releases, 1936-1943 (Box 14)
    - Registration, 1944; 1945 (Box 14)
    - Secretariat, 1930 (Box 14)
    - Workers (Communist) Party, 1929 (Box 14)
    - Westchester, Putnam, Rockland (NY), 1946 (Box 14)
    - Unidentified reports, undated (Box 14)
    - Fragments, undated (Box 15)
  - Communist Party, USA opposition, 1929; 1930,; 1933,; 1935,; 1936 (Box 15)
  - Communist Party, USA and Earl Browder v. Daily News, 1938 (Box 15)
  - Communist Party, USA v. Paul Peek, Secretary of State of California, 1942 (Box 15)
  - Communist Party, USA v. McFadden Publications, 1940 (Box 15)
  - Communist Party, Uruguay, 1939 (Box 15)
  - Communist Party, Venezuela, undated (Box 15)
  - Communist Party Workers School, 1925 (Box 15)
  - Communist Party World Congress of the Communist International (7th), 1935 (Box 15)
  - Communist Party Young Communist International, 1923 (Box 15)
  - Communist Party, Yugoslavia, 1947-1949 (Box 15)
  - Communist Party of the USA (Majority Group), See Communist Party, USA, opposition.
  - Communist Political Association
    - [General], 1945; 1946 (Box 15)
    - Constitution, 1944 (Box 15)
    - Election, 1948 (Box 15)
    - Financial reports, 1944; 1945 (Box 15)
    - National Committee, 1945 (Box 15)
    - Massachusetts, 1945 (Box 15)
    - New York State, 1944; 1945 (Box 15)
    - Ohio, 1945 (Box 15)
    - Press releases, 1944-1949 (Box 15)
    - Western Pennsylvania, West Virginia, 1945 (Box 15)
  - Communist Review, See Communist Party, Great Britain.
  - Community Church of Boston, 1938; 1939 (Box 16)
  - Community Church of New York, 1935 (Box 16)
  - Comrade X, See Liberty.
  - Confereration of Workers of Latin America (C.T.A.L.), 1944 (Box 16)
  - Conference to Coordinate War Efforts of Professional Men and Women, 1943 (Box 16)
  - Congress of Industrial Organizations (CIO), 1938; 1946,; 1947 (Box 16)
  - Congress of Industrial Organizations, Full Employment Committee, 1950 (Box 16)
  - Congress of Soviet-American Friendship, 1943 (Box 16)
  - Connecticut Conference on Social and Labor Leguslation, 1942 (Box 16)
  - Continental Artcrafts, Weston, MA, 1946 (Box 16)
  - Continental Congress of Authentically Democratic Parties, 1943 (Box 16)
  - Cook, Gerald, 1943 (Box 16)
  - Ćopić, Vladimir, 1938 (Box 16)
  - Cornell University, 1948 (Box 16)
  - Cornwall, Max, "Complete Index to 'A Textbook of Marxist Philosophy' ", 1940 (Box 16)
  - Coronet Magazine, 1947; 1954 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence Chess League of America, 1956 (Box 16)
  - Corretjer, Juan Antonio, 1942-1945 (Box 16)
    See also Pueblos Hispanos.
  - Coughlin, Charles Edward, See The Christian Front.
  - Council for Pan-American Democracy, 1939; 1944,; 1945 (Box 16)
  - Council on African Affairs, Inc., 1944; 1945 (Box 16)
  - Council of American Associations of Commerce and production, 1944 (Box 16)
  - "Court of Public Opinion," Dumont Television Network, 1948 (Box 16)
  - Cousins, Norman, 1946 (Box 16)
    See also Saturday Review.
  - Cox, Eugene A., 1943; 1944 (Box 16)
  - Crane-Gartz, Kate, 1938-1940 (Box 16)
  - Creative Age Press, Inc., 1946; 1947 (Box 16)
  - Criterion Books, Inc., 1957 (Box 16)
  - Croatians in America, undated (Box 16)
  - Crosbie, Paul, 1945 (Box 16)
  - Crow, Carl, 1938 (Box 16)
  - [Thomas Y.] Crowell Company, 1946; 1947 (Box 16)
  - Crown Publishers, 1946; 1947-1949 (Box 16)
  - Crowther, Geoffrey, 1944 (Box 16)
  - Cuba, 1943 (Box 16)
  - Curran, Edward Lodge, 1938; 1939 (Box 16)
  - Current Books, Inc., See [A.A.] Wyn, Inc.
  - Curtis Circulation Co., Inc., 1960 (Box 16)
  - Cuyahoga County Library, 1948 (Box 16)
  - Czechoslovak State Council, London, England, 1944 (Box 16)
  - Czechoslovakia, 1942 (Box 16)
  - D, 1942-1953 (Box 17)
  - The Daily Compass, 1950; 1951 (Box 17)
  - The Daily Worker, 1932-1947 (Box 17)
  - Dallas County (Texas) United Legislative Committee, 1944 (Box 17)
  - Dallin, David J., 1955; 1956 (Box 17)
  - Dana, Henry Wadsworth Longfellow, 1946 (Box 17)
  - Dance, 1947; 1948 (Box 17)
  - Daniel, Marion Price, Sr., 1957 (Box 17)
  - Darcy, Samuel, 1939; 1941,; 1942 (Box 17)
  - Davis, Benjamin J., Jr., 1942-1944 (Box 17)
  - Davis, Saville R., 1954 (Box 17)
  - [John] Day Company, 1947 (Box 17)
  - Deakin, Frederick William, 1963; 1964 (Box 17)
  - Dearborn (Michigan) Board of Education, 1948 (Box 17)
  - Debs, Eugene (Box 17)
  - Declaration of Interdependence, 1944 (Box 17)
  - Dedijer, Stevan, 1950; 1957,; 1959 (Box 17)
  - Defense Committee for Civil Rights for Communists, 1940 (Box 17)
  - Deleon, Daniel, 1920 (Box 17)
  - Demidov, K., 1946 (Box 17)
  - Democratic Socialist Party (Hungary), 1956 (Box 17)
  - Dennis, Eugene, 1943; undated (Box 17)
  - Detroit anti-labor agencies, undated (Box 17)
  - Deutsch, Albert, 1933 (Box 17)
  - Dial Press, Inc., 1933; 1942,; 1946,; 1947 (Box 17)
  - Dies Committee, See United States House of Representatives Special Committee on Un-American Activities
  - Dirksen, Everett M., 1946 (Box 17)
  - Disque, Brice P., 1954 (Box 17)
  - Distributors Guide, Inc., 1945; 1946 (Box 17)
  - Dodd, Bela V., 1949 (Box 17)
  - Doubleday & Company, Inc., 1946-1957 (Box 17)
  - Douglas, Paul Howard, 1957 (Box 17)
  - Douglas, Wallace, 1943; 1944 (Box 17)
  - Dover Publications, 1947 (Box 17)
  - Dowling, Lyle, 1942; 1943 (Box 17)
  - Drake America Corporation, 1947 (Box 18)
  - Draper, Theodore, 1955-1958; 1970 (Box 18)
  - Dreiser, Theodore, 1942; 1944 (Box 18)
  - Drinan, Robert F., 1974 (Box 18)
  - Dryden Press, Inc, 1947; 1960 (Box 18)
  - Dubinsky, David, 1944 (Box 18)
  - Duclos, Jacques, 1945; 1946 (Box 18)
  - Duell, Sloan and Pearce, Inc., 1946; 1947,; 1960,; 1961 (Box 18)
  - Duke University Library, 1948 (Box 18)
  - Duke University Press, 1946; 1947 (Box 18)
  - Dunn, Robert Williams, 1942 (Box 18)
  - Dunne, William Francis, 1930; 1938 (Box 18)
  - Durant, Will, See Declaration of Interdependence.
  - Dutt, Rajani Palme, 1944; 1945 (Box 18)
  - Dvorine, Israel, 1947 (Box 18)
  - E, 1943-1968 (Box 18)
  - Eastman, Max, 1942; 1945 (Box 18)
  - Economische Voorlichtingdienst, 1947 (Box 18)
  - Eddy, Montague, 1944 (Box 18)
  - Edelman, Irwin, 1946 (Box 18)
  - Eden, Robert Anthony, 1945 (Box 18)
  - [J. W.] Edwards Company, 1949 (Box 18)
  - Efries, Joseph, 1944; 1945 (Box 18)
  - Ehrlich, Henryk, See Ehrlich-Alter Case.
  - Ehrlich-Alter Case, 1943 (Box 18)
  - Electronics, 1947 (Box 18)
  - Embassy of the U.S.S.R., Washington, DC, 1946; 1947 (Box 18)
  - Emergency Civil Liberties Committee, 1954 (Box 18)
  - Emergency Conference for Aid to Spain, 1938 (Box 18)
  - Emerson Books, Inc, 1947 (Box 18)
  - Encina, Dionisio, undated (Box 18)
  - Encyclopædia Britannica Press, 1947 (Box 18)
  - [Irving] Ephraim, Booksellers, 1948 (Box 18)
  - Esquire, Inc, 1954 (Box 18)
  - The Evening Star, Washington, DC, 1948 (Box 18)
  - Ewert, Arthur, 1937 (Box 18)
  - F, 1940-1950 (Box 18)
  - Farm Journal, 1947 (Box 18)
  - Farmer-Labor Association of Minnesota, 1936 (Box 18)
  - Fascists in America, 1937 (Box 18)
  - Federal Union, Inc., 1942 (Box 18)
  - [Mitchell] Fein Associates, 1942; 1943 (Box 18)
  - Feingold vs. Board of Elections of Cook County, Illinois, 1942 (Box 18)
  - Fellowship of Reconciliation, 1936 (Box 18)
  - Fels, Samuel Simeon, 1943 (Box 18)
  - Ferrucci, Jerome, 1939 (Box 18)
  - Field, Frederick Vanderbilt, 1944; undated (Box 18)
  - Field, Marshall, III, 1945; 1947 (Box 18)
  - Fieldman, Solon, 1942 (Box 18)
  - Fine, Fred Morris, 1942 (Box 18)
  - Finland, 1919 (Box 18)
  - Fischer, Ruth, 1953 (Box 18)
  - Fish, Hamilton, III, 1938 (Box 18)
  - Flynn, Elizabeth Gurley, 1940-1944 (Box 19)
  - The Folger Shakespeare Library, 1946 (Box 19)
  - Foner, Philip S., See The Citadel Press.
  - Food Industries, 1947 (Box 19)
  - Footman, David, 1959; 1960 (Box 19)
  - Forbes, May (Mrs. Hank), 1946 (Box 19)
  - Ford, James W., 1940; 1942,; 1943 (Box 19)
  - Ford Hall Forum, Boston, Massachusetts, 1937; 1960 (Box 19)
  - Foreign Affairs Magazine, 1947 (Box 19)
  - Foreign Language Publishing House, Moscow, USSR, 1951 (Box 19)
  - Foreign Policy Association, 1938 (Box 19)
  - Forum Group, undated (Box 19)
  - Foster, William Zebulon, 1923-1951 (Box 19)
  - Foundation for Economic Education, Inc, 1948 (Box 19)
  - Four Continent Book Corporation, 1948; 1949 (Box 19)
  - France (Vichy), 1940 (Box 19)
  - Frank, Waldo, 1935-1937 (Box 19)
  - Franklin, Francis, 1948 (Box 19)
  - Free World Association, 1944 (Box 19)
  - Freeman, A.C. (pseudonym), See Chamberlin, William Henry.
  - Freeman, Joseph, 1956-1964 (Box 19)
  - Frequency Modulation Business, 1947 (Box 19)
  - Friedman, Robert, 1957 (Box 19)
  - Friends of Democracy, Inc., See Birkhead, Leon Milton.
  - Friends of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade, 1938 (Box 19)
  - Friends of the Debs Column, 1937 (Box 19)
  - Friends of the Soviet Union, 1930 (Box 19)
  - Fry, Varian, 1945 (Box 19)
  - Fuller, Alvan Tufts, 1927 (Box 19)
  - The Fund for the Republic, Inc., 1955-1957 (Box 19)
  - Funk and Wagnalls Company, 1944-1947 (Box 19)
  - G, 1939-1960 (Box 19)
  - Gaer Associates, Inc, 1949 (Box 19)
  - Gallagher, Leo, 1950 (Box 19)
  - Ganley, Nat, undated (Box 19)
  - Gantt, W. Horsley, 1948 (Box 19)
  - Garlin, Sender, 1943 (Box 19)
  - Garry, Shirley, 1952; undated (Box 19)
  - Gartz, Victor E., 1946 (Box 19)
  - Gates, Johnny, 1942; 1964 (Box 19)
  - Gauvreau, Emile, 1947 (Box 19)
  - Gazette des Beaux Arts, 1947 (Box 19)